<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: zsh | Bartj3]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.bartvanzon.com/blog/categories/zsh/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.bartvanzon.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-06T21:09:30+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.bartvanzon.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bart van Zon]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up your shell: oh-my-zsh]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.bartvanzon.com/blog/2013/10/16/setting-up-your-shell-oh-my-zsh/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-16T21:47:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.bartvanzon.com/blog/2013/10/16/setting-up-your-shell-oh-my-zsh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Up until not too long ago I barely used the terminal, I used it when absolutely
necessary but whenever it was possible I immediately switch to a GUI for
whatever I was doing. After reading yet another &ldquo;Why Vim is awesome&rdquo; blog I
decided to make the switch from Textmate to Vim. And once I was editing in Vim
I noticed that I was more productive by just fullscreening my terminal and
staying in the terminal as much as possible. Without continuously switching
between my mouse and keyboard I got faster and faster at the stuff I do most
of my day: coding and everything related to it. Since then I&rsquo;ve been trying to
optimize my work flow as much as possible.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The first step to having a pleasant terminal environment is getting the proper
shell. I&rsquo;ve picked <a href="https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh">oh-my-zsh</a>. Not
because I think zsh is way better then bash or the few other alternatives,
because I honestly wouldn&rsquo;t know whether it&rsquo;s actually better. But because
oh-my-zsh is crazy simple to install and configure, and instantly gives you
awesome benefits. One of the biggest is the auto completion, especially when
just getting started in terminal it&rsquo;s great when you vaguely remember a command
that you can just press tab and it&rsquo;ll suggest a bunch of commands for you to
use. Another great one is the theming options that come with oh-my-zsh. The
starting theme is awesome on itself, but whenever you have some spare time you
should really try customizing a theme to your own desire.</p>

<p>Installing
Obviously they&rsquo;ve got installing instructions
<a href="https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh">on their github page</a>, however if
you&rsquo;re a mac user installing oh-my-zsh is just a simple oneliner:
<code>
curl -L https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh/raw/master/tools/install.sh | sh
</code></p>

<p>Have fun!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
