<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bartj3</title>
    <description>...
</description>
    <link>http://www.bartvanzon.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.bartvanzon.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 15:47:27 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 15:47:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rails tree structure</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago I had to make a documents/folder structure for an app. The
idea was that there’s two types of objects: &lt;strong&gt;categories&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;documents&lt;/strong&gt;,
the user can click through categories and download documents. A category can
contain other categories and documents. We only had to show the category the
user is currently in, the files and categories that are in that category and
some way to navigate one level higher. So there was no need to see children’s
children etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick search on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruby-toolbox.com&quot;&gt;Ruby Toolbox&lt;/a&gt; shows
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stefankroes/ancestry&quot;&gt;Ancestry&lt;/a&gt; and a bunch of other options
but most of them are way to complicated for the simple goal I was trying to
achieve so I’ve decided to build it from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out with two models, the Category model, and the Document model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;``` ruby app/models/category.rb
class Category &amp;lt; ActiveRecord::Base
  belongs_to :parent, class_name: ‘Category’, foreign_key: “parent_id”
  validates :title, presence: true
  has_many :documents&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;def children
    self.class.where(parent_id: id)
  end&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;def parent_title
    parent.title if parent.present?
  end
end
```&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The category can belong to other categories, and that optional parent is stored
in the &lt;code&gt;parent_id&lt;/code&gt; variable. A category has a title as we need something to show
when listing the categories and a category can have several documents in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby app/models/document.rb
class Document &amp;lt; ActiveRecord::Base
  validates :title, presence: true
  belongs_to :category
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documents have a title to display them (and in a real world application probably
a file to go with it) and it may belong to a category. If it has no category it
should be displayed on the top level of the tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;``` ruby db/schema.rb
create_table “categories”, force: true do |t|
  t.string   “title”
  t.integer  “parent_id”
end&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;create_table “documents”, force: true do |t|
  t.string   “title”
  t.integer  “category_id”
end
```
The database schema should look something like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the problems with these models is that a category can reference to ANY
category as it’s parent. So even itself, to prevent that we’ll need a custom
validator, it can be added to the category model with the following line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby app/models/category.rb
validates_with CategoryParentValidator
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the validator itself would look something like this:
&lt;code&gt;ruby app/validators/category_parent_validator.rb
Class CategoryParentValidator &amp;lt; ActiveModel::Validator
  def validate(record)
    if !record.new_record? &amp;amp;&amp;amp; record.parent_id == record.id
      record.errors[:parent] &amp;lt;&amp;lt; I18n.t(&#39;cant_be_itself&#39;, scope: &#39;errors.messages&#39;)
    end
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;
If the record is new we shouldn’t check if the parent_id is the same as the
current id because the current id will be nil. So a new record without a parent
would have both id’s on nil but is still valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step in building the tree structure is the controller:
``` ruby app/controllers/documents_controller.rb
class DocumentsController &amp;lt; ApplicationController
  before_action :set_document, only: [:show]
  before_action :set_files_variables, only: [:index, :show]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;def index
  end&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;def show
  end&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;private
  def set_document
    @document = Document.find params[:id]
  end&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;def set_files_variables
    @selected_category = params[:selected_category]
    @parent_category = get_parent_category_id(@selected_category)
    @categories = Category.where(parent_id: @selected_category)
    @documents = Document.where(category_id: @selected_category)
  end&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;def get_parent_category_id(category_id)
    begin
      selected_category = Category.find(category_id)
      return selected_category.parent.id if selected_category.parent.present?
    rescue ActiveRecord::RecordNotFound
    end&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;nil #the category was not found or there was no parent   end end ``` There&#39;s a bunch of variables we&#39;re going to need in the view, the selected category is needed so we can show the title of the category we&#39;re currently in. The parent_category is needed to navigate to one level higher, the categories are the categories in the selected category and the documents are the documents in the selected category.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;``` erb app/views/documents/_document_list.html.erb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Document List&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;document_list&quot;&gt;
  &amp;lt;% if @selected_category.present? %&amp;gt;
    &lt;li class=&quot;parent&quot;&gt;
    &amp;lt;%= link_to &#39;..&#39;, documents_path(selected_category: @parent_category) %&amp;gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &amp;lt;% end %&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;% @categories.each do |category| %&amp;gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;category&quot;&gt;
    &amp;lt;%= link_to &quot;#{category.title}&quot;, documents_path(selected_category: category.id) %&amp;gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&amp;lt;% end %&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;% @documents.each do |document| %&amp;gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;document &amp;lt;%= document_icon_class(document) %&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;
    &amp;lt;%= link_to &quot;#{document.title}&quot;, document_path(document, selected_category: @selected_category) %&amp;gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&amp;lt;% end %&amp;gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;```
I expected the view to be pretty complex but it turned out to be easier then I
expected. We show the selected category, a way of navigating and a list of
categories and files in the category. Because there’s no need to see children’s
children this stays pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 15:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bartvanzon.com/rails/2013/11/21/rails-tree-structure.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bartvanzon.com/rails/2013/11/21/rails-tree-structure.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blogging with Vim</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Writings blog posts with Vim is awesome! Obviously, if I thought otherwise I
wouldn’t currently be writing this in Vim. Writing posts on my local machine
works perfectly for me as interruptions aren’t as big of a problem as they
would be when I’d be writing in some textarea online. I can just close the file,
pick up whatever is interrupting me and continue whenever I want. Another nice
thing is that I often write posts while traveling by public transport and
writing the posts on my local machine means I don’t have to rely on the internet
the public transport offers (which actually isn’t too bad in the Netherlands).
Another thing that blogging in Vim makes possible is that you can just open a
single terminal screen, set it to fullscreen and write without any distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging in Vim wouldn’t be half as cool if you wouldn’t be able to deploy your
markdown files straight to your blog from the commandline. Blogging from your
terminal, everyone wants that right? Or is it just for weird developers? Ah
well… &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/imathis/octopress&quot;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; makes this possible!
You can write your post in markdown, run a rake command and tadaaa: it’s
deployed and online for everyone to read! To get started with Octopress it will
take some minor configuration, or if you’re anything like me a lot of
configuration but once setup it’s a great way to blog.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://octopress.org&quot;&gt;The Octopress site&lt;/a&gt; has plenty of guides explaining
where to get started and where to start tweaking if you want a custom solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a couple of downsides of writing in Vim which are fixable by setting
your configuration properly. By default there’s no line breaking in Vim so if
you would just start typing away all of your text will end up becoming one long
giant line of text. This is fixable by typing &lt;code&gt;:set textwidth=80&lt;/code&gt;, keeping your
lines under 80 lines is a great convention while coding. But it works great for
keeping your texts readable as well. This is a setting I do not have in my
.vimrc because I only want this set while writing blog posts, automatic
line breaks are probably a bad idea while coding. I do have the setting
&lt;code&gt;:set colorcolumn=80&lt;/code&gt; in my .vimrc which shows where the 80th character is in
every line so I can (attempt) to stay under the 80 char limit manually while
coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you already started on your post without setting text width or if you
copy-pasted something and ruined your formatting you can select the text using
visualmode and type &lt;code&gt;gq&lt;/code&gt; to reformat all of the selected text. Obviously it
would be even better if you use &lt;code&gt;gg{motion}&lt;/code&gt; to achieve the same with less
keystrokes but personally I often use visualmode for this action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me one of the biggest loss when using Vim is the lack of spell checking,
because English isn’t my native tongue I &lt;s&gt;definately&lt;/s&gt; definitely need it
(and to be honest I a need it when writing Dutch texts as well). Of course
spell checking is something you can turn on, and with plenty of supported
languages. To turn spell checking on and highlight the incorrectly spelled words
use the command &lt;code&gt;:setlocal spell spelllang=en_us&lt;/code&gt;. You can then navigate
forwards (&lt;code&gt;]s&lt;/code&gt;) and backwards (&lt;code&gt;[s&lt;/code&gt;) through these incorrectly spelled words and
by using the &lt;code&gt;z=&lt;/code&gt; command you’ll open up the list with correct spelling
suggestions. When writing tech articles there’ll probably be a bunch of words
that are not in the list and thus incorrectly marked as incorrect. You can add
these words to the wordlist by using the &lt;code&gt;zg&lt;/code&gt; command. There’s an enormous
amount of alternative commands when fixing your typo’s and spelling errors,
be sure to check out the relative help files at &lt;code&gt;:h spell&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of these settings have shortcuts which make them easier to type out, Vim
help will tell you about them. For example &lt;code&gt;:help textwidth&lt;/code&gt; (or even &lt;code&gt;:h
textwidth&lt;/code&gt;, we are lazy devs!) will tell you that setting &lt;code&gt;:set tw&lt;/code&gt; will do
exactly the same! And while you’re in the help files anyways &lt;code&gt;:h set&lt;/code&gt; will tell
you that you should use &lt;code&gt;:se tw=80&lt;/code&gt; next time you’re setting your text width!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 08:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bartvanzon.com/vim/2013/11/16/blogging-with-vim.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bartvanzon.com/vim/2013/11/16/blogging-with-vim.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>vim</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Configure your Vim for easy searching</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When navigating through Vim you’ll search a lot using the &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; command, which
works ‘ok’ by default but there’s a couple of settings you can make to increase
Vims search functionality a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the settings I have in my &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
set incsearch
&lt;/code&gt;
Normally Vim will wait with searching until you’ve completed your search pattern
and once you press enter it will search for a match. Once you’ve set &lt;code&gt;incearch&lt;/code&gt;
it will immediately start searching as you type. So you’ll see where the first
match of your search pattern is, pretty handy as you’ll immediately see whether
your pattern is correct or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
set hlsearch
&lt;/code&gt;
This will highlight all of the matches of your search pattern, making it easy to
show where and how often your pattern matches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
autocmd InsertEnter * :setlocal nohlsearch
autocmd InsertLeave * :setlocal hlsearch
&lt;/code&gt;
This will disable the highlights when you enter insertmode and will turn them
back on when you leave insertmode. So if you’ve searched and want to change
something it’ll stop highlighting the results but once you’re done editing
you’ll be able to continue your search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
map &amp;lt;Leader&amp;gt;cs :nohlsearch&amp;lt;cr&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
Highlighting your results is great, but you’ll want to turn the highlights off
once you’re done with them. Typing &lt;code&gt;:nohlsearch&lt;/code&gt; will do the trick, but as this
is something I do quite often I’ve created a shortcut for it: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Leader&amp;gt;cs&lt;/code&gt;
clears all the search results (&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;lear &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;earch).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s plenty more stuff to tweak about searching through Vim, these are the
ones I’ve set but if you want to learn more tricks be sure to check out Vim’s
awesome help guides. They’ve got an entire chapter about searching, check it out
at: &lt;code&gt;:h usr_27&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I searching through my files the hard way or am I missing an awesome setting?
Please let me know in the comments, via mail or on Twitter!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 18:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bartvanzon.com/vim/2013/11/12/configure-your-vim-for-easy-searching.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bartvanzon.com/vim/2013/11/12/configure-your-vim-for-easy-searching.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>vim</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keeping your workspace in sync using Dropbox</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I spend most of my time working on two systems, a desktop at work and a laptop
at home. As I spend a lot of that time in the terminal I’ve setup some things to
make sure my shell works exactly the same on both systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve this I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://db.tt/gpBR2QOx&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; to sync all of my
dotfiles, if you haven’t used Dropbox before you should definately give it a go.
It’s a tool that keeps a folder in sync between your separate computer systems
(and phone) with the nice bonus of automaticly saving previous versions of all
of those files so if you accidentaly remove or overwrite one you can get it back
easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my Dropbox folder I’ve got a folder called &lt;code&gt;global files/dotfiles&lt;/code&gt; which
contains a lot of my dotfiles. The files and folders I keep in there are:
&lt;code&gt;.gemrc .gitconfig, .gitignore_global, .oh-my-zsh, .railsrc, .tmux.conf, .vim,
.vimrc, .zsh_history, .zshenv&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously you should judge for yourself what files you will put in there but
these files are the ones that make sense for me to keep in sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep the files in sync you’ll have to copy the originals files to your
dropbox folder and create a symlink to the Dropbox location in the old folder.
For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
cd ~
mv .gemrc Dropbox/global\ files/dotfiles/.gemrc
ln -s Dropbox/global\ files/dotfiles/.gemrc .gemrc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this your editor and shell should work exactly the same on all of your
systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 08:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bartvanzon.com/dotfiles/2013/11/07/keeping-your-workspace-in-sync-using-dropbox.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bartvanzon.com/dotfiles/2013/11/07/keeping-your-workspace-in-sync-using-dropbox.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>dotfiles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting on your vimconfig</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve installed Vim(didn’t install it yet?
&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2013/11/03/getting-started-with-vim/&quot;&gt;check out this blogpost&lt;/a&gt;) it’s time
to setup your configuration file, where the Vim magic happens. Vim
configurations are different for each developer, you start out with a blank
configuration file, or maybe with a copy of a vimrc of a developer you know and
over the years as you grow as a developer your vimrc will grow with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your vimrc is something to be proud of, it shows what awesome work flow
improvements you’ve made and it shows how you know how to mold your tools
completely to work for you. A lot of developers share their dot files on GitHub
and if the developer’s a Vim user it’s very likely you can find his vimrc there
as well. Vims configuration file can be found in &lt;code&gt;~/.vimrc&lt;/code&gt;, and obviously the
best way to edit it is in Vim. But as you might need some time to get used to
editing text and navigating through it in Vim you could of course open it in
your (previous) favorite text editor as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll show you some of the lines you can put in your vimrc that I have in there,
and of which I believe you really can’t do without. If you would like to know
more about a setting then I explained about it, remember that you can use Vim
help for all of this stuff (for example &lt;code&gt;:h nocompatible&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
set nocompatible
&lt;/code&gt;
This will tell Vim to actually behave like Vim, and not try to be compatible
with Vi. An old editor which was created way before I was even born, so I can’t
really be bothered about compatibility with it. I should probably look up what
the exact differences are but I was told this should be in there, so now I’m
telling you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
syntax enable
&lt;/code&gt;
Tell Vim to use color syntax highlighting, this will make coding a lot more
pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
nnoremap &amp;lt;Left&amp;gt; :echoe &quot;Use h&quot;&amp;lt;CR&amp;gt;
nnoremap &amp;lt;Right&amp;gt; :echoe &quot;Use l&quot;&amp;lt;CR&amp;gt;
nnoremap &amp;lt;Up&amp;gt; :echoe &quot;Use k&quot;&amp;lt;CR&amp;gt;
nnoremap &amp;lt;Down&amp;gt; :echoe &quot;Use j&quot;&amp;lt;CR&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
I actually don’t have these in my vimrc anymore but used to have this for quite
a while. In Vim you really (really!) shouldn’t use the arrow keys for
navigation, I had a hard time doing so, so I used this set of configurations to
disable the key and tell me what key to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
set autoindent
set smartindent
set tabstop=2
set shiftwidth=2
set expandtab
set copyindent
set listchars=tab:··,trail:·
set list
&lt;/code&gt;
Auto indentation makes your life easier, these settings won’t only take care of
your indentation, they will also make sure you’re using spaces instead of tabs
for indentation. And last but not least they’ll show you if the person before
you messed his tabs/spaces up by showing tabs in your code and showing trailing
spaces. The whole tabs vs spaces ends up being your personal preference so you
might want to tweak this to match your own preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
set cursorline
&lt;/code&gt;
It highlights the entire line your cursor is on, not quite a must have, but I
think it just makes coding a bit more pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
set colorcolumn=80
&lt;/code&gt;
You should really try to keep your lines shorter then 80 characters, it makes
your code way easier to read and has the nice advantage that you can actually
split screen your code on a laptop as well. This setting will draw a line at the
80 character limit, it’s not prohibiting you from creating longer lines, but
just subtly reminding you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
let mapleader=&quot;,&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;
A lot of the shortcuts in Vim use the leader key to trigger them, (and the longer
you’re developing the more you’ll create) the default leader key however is &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt;
which is pretty annoying, the comma is easy to reach so mapping the leader key to
your comma will make a lot of your shortcuts easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
set backspace=2
&lt;/code&gt;
By default Vim can have some pretty weird behaviors, this corrects one of them.
For example: Vim won’t remove newlines with backspace by default. Annoying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
set history=1000
&lt;/code&gt;
When using Vim in normal mode (where you enter the commands) you can navigate
through your previous commands using the arrow keys, by default it stores the
last 20 commands you gave Vim which normally should be more then enough. But it
never hurts to be safe, in case you forgot that awesome command you used a while
ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
set relativenumber
&lt;/code&gt;
This is an incredible setting which took me way to long to find, navigating to
Vim can be a guess sometimes, you want to delete the piece of code in the next
couple of lines but how many lines is it exactly? You’re at line 15, the other
code is at line 29, so thats 14 lines… These simple calculations will take a
slight amount of your time which would have been better spend coding. Relative
numbers will show you relative line numbers. Which means that in the gutter
where normally the line numbers start with 1 at the top of the file and go down
the gutter will show the current line as 0, the line above and below it as 1,
and above and below that as 2 etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
set encoding=utf-8
&lt;/code&gt;
This one should be pretty obvious: it sets the character encoding used inside
Vim, it’s not default though so make sure you set it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vim
nmap k gk
nmap j gj
&lt;/code&gt;
When using &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt; to navigate up and down your code you expect to go to the
next line on your screen, thats not default though. Vim will send you to the
next line in the file, which if Vim wrapped the line because your screen’s too
small might not be exactly what you meant. This completely annoyed me so I
remapped &lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;gk&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gj&lt;/code&gt; which will make them behave like I want
them to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These configurations are just the tip of the iceberg, there are way more options
to configure, but these should get you started. Make sure to browse through
other people’s configurations as often as possible to learn new tricks and keep
tweaking your configuration to make your Vim the best there is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be writing more posts about Vim (&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/categories/vim/&quot;&gt;read more&lt;/a&gt;), so
make sure to read those too, expect articles about plugins, workflows and more!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 19:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bartvanzon.com/vim/2013/11/04/starting-on-your-vimconfig.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bartvanzon.com/vim/2013/11/04/starting-on-your-vimconfig.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>vim</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting started with Vim</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve started using Vim about a year ago, so I’m definitely not an experienced
user. But along the way I’ve learned some neat tricks which I would like to
share with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First there’s installing Vim itself, sure if you’re a Mac user Vim comes
preinstalled. But if you want it to play nice with some of the available plugins
you’ll need a Vim that’s been compiled with Ruby support. On a Mac there’s a
couple ways to do it:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The awesome way&lt;/strong&gt;: Google like crazy, find the correct
files, setup the configuration properly and compile it yourself. I’ve tried this
a while ago and got this working in a couple of hours, sadly I broke it several
weeks later and never got it working again.&lt;br /&gt;
Luckily there’s another way, &lt;strong&gt;The lazy way&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;brew install macvim&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve got Vim running it’s time for the hard part, actually using it. When
you’re coming from an editor like Textmate or Sublime or maybe even a complete
IDE Vim will take some getting used to. Luckily Vim has an insanely good
help file. When you start Vim just access it by typing &lt;code&gt;:h&lt;/code&gt;. EVERYTHING is
different in Vim, and made for developer happiness, even something as simply
navigation through a file. Sure you can use the arrow keys to move around, but
there’s ways way more effective than that, and the help file will slowly guide
you through those ways. Just start reading the help file and instead of an
enormous list of options it’ll tell you step by step how to get started. After
you’ve got the basic hang of (very simple) navigation it’ll suggest you to use
vimtutor and I completely agree. Vimtutor is an awesome tool to learn the Vim
basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve installed Vim and worked your way through Vimtutor it’s time to
configure Vim to your own taste, I’ll explain where to get started in a blogpost
tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 10:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bartvanzon.com/vim/2013/11/03/getting-started-with-vim.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bartvanzon.com/vim/2013/11/03/getting-started-with-vim.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>vim</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Switching Postgresql on a Mac</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier today I decided to switch from &lt;a href=&quot;http://postgresapp.com&quot;&gt;Postgres.app&lt;/a&gt; to
a simple homebrew install of postgresql. Not because I’m not satisfied with the
app but I think it’s just a bit overkill to start up a database. Together with
the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mperham/lunchy&quot;&gt;lunchy gem&lt;/a&gt; (a launchctl wrapper)
I found yesterday switching should be a piece of cake. So I threw Postgres.app
in the trashbin. Entered &lt;code&gt;brew install postgresql&lt;/code&gt; and everything was supposed
to be unicorns and rainbows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I kept getting this error when trying to interact with the database via
Rails:
&lt;code&gt;
could not connect to server: No such file or directory
Is the server running locally and accepting
connections on Unix domain socket &quot;/var/pgsql_socket/.s.PGSQL.5432&quot;?
&lt;/code&gt;
I had absolutely no clue where to look but after a while of messing around I
figured it out, the &lt;code&gt;pg&lt;/code&gt; gem I use with Rails was installed with the old
Postgresql installed. And now I switched databases it couldn’t connect anymore.
The solution is simple, &lt;strong&gt;just uninstall the pg gem and reinstall it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 09:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bartvanzon.com/2013/11/02/switching-postgresql-on-a-mac.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bartvanzon.com/2013/11/02/switching-postgresql-on-a-mac.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The world of Objective-C through Ruby eyes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My contract says &lt;em&gt;Developer&lt;/em&gt; which might sound a bit allround but up until
recently 95% of the development I did was Ruby on Rails. With a rare sidestep
to Actionscript, Objective-C, Coffeescript, plain Ruby and more. I’ve always
wanted to do some more Objective-C and in my spare time I’ve made one or two
apps in the past (actually one finished and about 10 started but never finished
;)) But I believe the only way to learn something properly is by doing it 40
hours a week. So a couple of weeks ago I’ve finally had the luck that we
(Wirelab) got an Objective-C job and it was quiet enough for me to focus on
picking up Objective-C and building the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’m a Ruby developer and more specifically a Rails developer I’m quite a lazy
developer. When I run into a problem more often then not there’s a gem to solve
it for me or there’s a blog that explains step by step how to solve it. Rarely
I spend days or even hours on a single problem anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it was quite a shock for me to find the state the Objective-C “community” is
in. I say “community” because I’ve probably looked for it in the wrong places,
but the blogposts, tutorials and stack overflow answers (and questions) seem to
be of a poor quality compared with Ruby. The pride that ruby developers have in
their work doesn’t seem to be present in the Objective-C scene: if it works its
good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want my code to work, I want my code to &lt;strong&gt;shine&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ve been lucky to
have a friend who’s an experienced Objective-C developer that has been pushing
me in the right direction last couple of weeks because I haven’t found the
shining ambition a lot online. Like I’ve said before maybe I’ve just been
looking in the wrong places so please do correct me if I’m wrong. One awesome
thing the Objective-C community does have is &lt;a href=&quot;http://cocoapods.org/&quot;&gt;Cocoapods&lt;/a&gt;.
On there I’ve found great pods (Objective-C’s gems) like
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AFNetworking/AFNetworking&quot;&gt;AFNetworking&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samvermette/SVProgressHUD&quot;&gt;SVProgressHUD&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gotosleep/JASidePanels&quot;&gt;JASidePanels&lt;/a&gt; and many more. It’s
not only an easy way to find these gems to make your life easier, it’s also a
place to display your own shining code. (There is one thing wrong with these pods
though… They’re named after the thing they actually do! Aweful, I’ve always
loved the smart gem names like Nokogiri, Capybara and Koala.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to share my way of being a lazy developer with the Objective-C developers
so I’ve decided to build some gems, or actually I should say pods. As a fresh
developer I will probably mess some things up badly, but I might also fix some
stuff thats weird for me but the experienced developers take for granted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I’ve worked on &lt;code&gt;NSDate+RelativeTime&lt;/code&gt;, a pod you can find on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://cocoapods.org/?q=nsdate%20relative%20time%20bart&quot;&gt;Cocoapods&lt;/a&gt; or on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bartj3/NSDate-RelativeTime&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. It got some positive
feedback since I’ve posted it so I’ll assume people are using it. Sadly there’s
no actual stats on pod usage like there is with Rubygems. And I’ve got another
pod in the works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty satisfied with the result as it solves a problem I ran into a couple
of weeks ago and there didn’t seem to be anything like this yet so I hope it
helps some other developers be lazy like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thing in the pod that definitely doesn’t shine yet is it’s tests. Testing
with Objective-C, and especially continuous integration seems to be way harder
then it is with Ruby. And most of the resources I found were outdated. It
frustrates me I need to generate an entire project while there’s only one file
with actual tests. And besides that only IOS is tested while it should work fine
on OSX as well, but I don’t have the tests to prove it. If there’s anyone out
there who would like to pair with me to get some more robust tests running and
getting some kind of CI setup that’d be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;im-a-lazy-developer-and-working-on-making-objective-c-developers-just-as-lazy-as-me&quot;&gt;I’m a lazy developer and working on making Objective-C developers just as lazy as me!&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 20:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bartvanzon.com/ruby/objective-c/2013/10/30/the-world-of-objective-c-through-ruby-eyes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bartvanzon.com/ruby/objective-c/2013/10/30/the-world-of-objective-c-through-ruby-eyes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        <category>objective-c</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting up your shell: oh-my-zsh</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Up until not too long ago I barely used the terminal, I used it when absolutely
necessary but whenever it was possible I immediately switch to a GUI for
whatever I was doing. After reading yet another “Why Vim is awesome” blog I
decided to make the switch from Textmate to Vim. And once I was editing in Vim
I noticed that I was more productive by just fullscreening my terminal and
staying in the terminal as much as possible. Without continuously switching
between my mouse and keyboard I got faster and faster at the stuff I do most
of my day: coding and everything related to it. Since then I’ve been trying to
optimize my work flow as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step to having a pleasant terminal environment is getting the proper
shell. I’ve picked &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh&quot;&gt;oh-my-zsh&lt;/a&gt;. Not
because I think zsh is way better then bash or the few other alternatives,
because I honestly wouldn’t know whether it’s actually better. But because
oh-my-zsh is crazy simple to install and configure, and instantly gives you
awesome benefits. One of the biggest is the auto completion, especially when
just getting started in terminal it’s great when you vaguely remember a command
that you can just press tab and it’ll suggest a bunch of commands for you to
use. Another great one is the theming options that come with oh-my-zsh. The
starting theme is awesome on itself, but whenever you have some spare time you
should really try customizing a theme to your own desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing
Obviously they’ve got installing instructions
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh&quot;&gt;on their github page&lt;/a&gt;, however if
you’re a mac user installing oh-my-zsh is just a simple oneliner:
&lt;code&gt;
curl -L https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh/raw/master/tools/install.sh | sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 21:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bartvanzon.com/shell/zsh/2013/10/16/setting-up-your-shell-oh-my-zsh.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bartvanzon.com/shell/zsh/2013/10/16/setting-up-your-shell-oh-my-zsh.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>shell</category>
        
        <category>zsh</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yet another shot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years I tried blogging a couple of times. However for some reason I
never seemed able to get some rhythm in it, to keep blogging. The last article
on this blog is well over a year old. And the day I wrote it I was sure it was
the first of many more to come. The post got some traction on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; and I got some great feedback.
However the article was a rant, and rants always seem to get traction, and are
the easiest to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last couple of months I’ve had the honor to be invited to speak at a couple of
usergroups and conferences, and I got some great feedback. People were
enthoustiastic about what I had to tell them, a surprise to me because I thought
my skills to be pretty mediocre. Turns out that I might be comparing myself with
the wrong people. There’ll always be some guy better at Vim, or some guy better
at Ruby, and sadly for me plenty of guys better at skateboarding and
snowboarding… but (this sounds obvious but wasn’t to me) as it turns out
there’s a lot of people that have different focusses when learning new things.
People I can definately teach some new tricks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.jenniferdewalt.com/post/62998082815/after-180-websites-im-ready-to-start-the-rest-of-my&quot;&gt;Jennifer Dewalt&lt;/a&gt;
who created 180 websites in 180 days, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://swizec.com/blog/inspired-by-the-180-websites-i-will-understand-52-academic-papers-in-52-weeks/swizec/6365&quot;&gt;Swizec Teller&lt;/a&gt;
whose plan it is to understand 52 academic papers in 52 weeks I’ve set my own
goal: I’m not going to do anything daily, that’ll drive me crazy but I will try
to blog as often as possible with an absolute minimum of 2 blogs a week. They
don’t have to be pagelong stories, they could be glorified tweets, but as a
fulltime developer I learn something new every day and I experience something
weird at least once an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So expect some rants but hopefully mostly tips about vim, tmux, ruby, my
workflow, my workspace, crazy hacks, conferences, weird experiences and more!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 08:07:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bartvanzon.com/2013/10/15/yet-another-shot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bartvanzon.com/2013/10/15/yet-another-shot.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
